Guide to the Jack Shoemaker Papers, 1992-1994
Department of Special Collections
Jack Shoemaker Papers,
1992-1994
Special Collections M710
Shoemaker, Jack
24 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Purchased, 1994
BIOGRAPHY
Book publisher, editor, and one-time seller (the bookstore/press Sand Dollar Books was a Shoemaker venture) Jack Shoemaker has participated in and made great contribution to virtually every facet of the publishing industry. With William Turnbull, he founded the venerable North Point Press in Berkeley, which published 365 books in its 12-year life span. When North Point closed in 1991, Shoemaker moved to Pantheon Books, where he served as West Coast Editor and developed the manuscripts which make up the bulk of this collection. In 1994 he left the Bay Area for Washington, D.C., where he is editor-in-chief at Counterpoint, a literary publisher whose authors include MFK Fisher, Gary Snyder, and Wendell Berry, whose editorial association with Shoemaker spans his tenure at North Point and Pantheon.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Jack Shoemaker's professional and literary archives represent a variety of personal and professional interests, including a number of unpublished or shelved manuscripts whose provenance is unclear. For this reason, the archive has been subdivided into a number of smaller series, usually organized alphabetically.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- SERIES I: Professional: Pantheon Client Documents
  Contains mainly art, sales, marketing, and editorial correspondence concerning Shoemaker's clients at Pantheon West
- SERIES II: Pantheon Correspondence and Subject Files
  General topics and correspondence from the years 1991-4, when Shoemaker worked for Pantheon.
- SERIES III: Production and Promotion
  A collection of documents detailing more general production and development issues
- SERIES IV: Publishers (Incl. Pantheon non-list business)
  Contains general information about other publishing houses, as well as Pantheon's non-list business.
- SERIES V: Personal Projects and Subject Files
  The difference between "personal subject files" and "unpublished manuscripts" comes down to size and to level of perceived professional interest: some of the books in the unpublished MSS category had been under contract with North Point Press before it closed and the contracts were nullified when Pantheon chose not to take on the editing; some MSS were under discussion at Pantheon or North Point and ultimately shelved; some are large and unwieldy manuscripts without correspondence to indicate whether the manuscript was retained for its personal interest to Shoemaker himself or for possible publication.
- SERIES VI: Unpublished Manuscripts
- SERIES VII: Pantheon Manuscripts
  Consists of draft copies of the Pantheon West books themselves.
- SERIES VIII: Personal Collection
  A very small series of bound materials which were found apart from the others, perhaps because they were last-minute additions to the archive: an undated address book, a two-volume source book from the 1993 "Art of the Wild" Conference, and proofs for two books published by Parallax Press whose main interest to Shoemaker seems to be personal--The Awakening of the West because of its link to the Zen practice and publishing with which Shoemaker is associated; and the Petra Kelly essays because of their concern with environmentalism.
- SERIES IX: Photos
  The photo collection is arranged alphabetically by name, where subject is identifiable.
CONTAINER LIST
- SERIES I: Professional: Pantheon Client Documents
  - Kathy Acker: My Mother: Demonology: contract (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kathy Acker: My Mother: Demonology: correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kathy Acker: My Mother: Demonology: editorial (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kathy Acker: My Mother: Demonology: marketing & publicity (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kathy Acker: My Mother: Demonology: pre-signing (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kathy Acker: My Mother: Demonology: reviews (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas; art & production (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: background (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: contract/ P & L (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: correspondence (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: marketing/ reviews (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: editorial: draft #1, May 2, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: draft #2, Apr. 2, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: final draft (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: Robert Aitken: Encouraging Words; art /production (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: contract (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: copy (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: corrections (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: correspondence (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: editorial (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: marketing & publicity (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Robert Aitken: Dragon Gathas: p & l (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Wendell Berry: Entries: New Poems; contract (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Wendell Berry: Entries: New Poems: draft (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Wendell Berry: Entries: New Poems: draft #2: "unedited gathering; 9-15-92" (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Wendell Berry: Entries: New Poems: pre-signing (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Wendell Berry: Entries: New Poems: subrights (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Berry: Fidelity; art and production (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Berry: Fidelity: contracts (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Berry: Fidelity: copy (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Berry: Fidelity: correspondence (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Berry: Fidelity: editorial (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Berry: Fidelity: marketing/ publicity; interoffice (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Berry: Fidelity: marketing/publicity; reviews and reprints (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Berry: Fidelity: marketing/ publicity; schedules and receipts (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Berry: Fidelity: p & l (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Berry: Fidelity: reviews and blurbs (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Berry: Fidelity: subrights (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Berry: Harlan Hubbard; art and production (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Berry: Harlan Hubbard: contracts (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Berry: Harlan Hubbard: copy (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Berry: Harlan Hubbard: marketing/publicity (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Berry: Harlan Hubbard: p & l (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Berry: Harlan Hubbard: reviews (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Berry: Sex, Economy, Freedom & Community; art and production (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Berry: Sex, Economy, Freedom & Community: contracts (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Berry: Sex, Economy, Freedom & Community: copy (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Berry: Sex, Economy, Freedom & Community: editorial (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Berry: Sex, Economy, Freedom & Community: marketing and publicity (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Berry: Sex, Economy, Freedom & Community: permissions and copyrights (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Berry: Sex, Economy, Freedom & Community: presigning (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Berry: Sex, Economy, Freedom & Community: subrights (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Berry: reviews of North Point Press books (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - John Daniel: Toward Oregon: proposal (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home; art and production (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: blurbs (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: contracts (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: copy (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: corrections (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: correspondence (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: editorial: agenting/sales (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: editorial: Wendell Berry correspondence (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: editorial: correspondence (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: editorial: drafts (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: marketing: author information (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: marketing: author questionnaire (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: marketing: blurb solicitations (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: marketing: memos (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: marketing: sales lists and reading schedules (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: permissions: citations (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: permissions: reprints (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: presigning (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: reviews (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - John Daniel: The Trail Home: subrights (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind; advertising (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind: art and production (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind: author bibliography (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind: contracts (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind: copy (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind: correspondence (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind: p & l (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind: reviews (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Guy Davenport: The Geography of the Mind: subrights (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - M.F.K. Fisher, To Begin Again (form'ly Legend of Love); art and production (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - M.F.K. Fisher, To Begin Again (form'ly Legend of Love): contract (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - M.F.K. Fisher, To Begin Again (form'ly Legend of Love): copy (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - M.F.K. Fisher, To Begin Again (form'ly Legend of Love): correspondence (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - M.F.K. Fisher, To Begin Again (form'ly Legend of Love): editorial (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - M.F.K. Fisher, To Begin Again (form'ly Legend of Love): permission (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - M.F.K. Fisher, To Begin Again (form'ly Legend of Love): p & l (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - M.F.K. Fisher, To Begin Again (form'ly Legend of Love): old North Point Reviews (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: The Boss Dog; art and production (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: The Boss Dog: author bio (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: The Boss Dog: copy (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: The Boss Dog: contract (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: The Boss Dog: p & l (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: The Boss Dog: reviews (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: Stay Me: art and production (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: Stay Me: contracts (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: Stay Me: copy (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: Stay Me: editorial (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: Stay Me: legal (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: Stay Me: permissions and rights (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: Stay Me: p & l (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: advertising: general, Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: adv/ marketing: readings and schedules (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: sales figures (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: art: general (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: art: pasteup (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: blurbs (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: contract (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: copy (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: editorial: copy edit #1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: editorial: copy edit #2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: editorial: general (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: permissions (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: promo copy (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: p & l (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: subrights (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Anne Lamott, Operating Instructions: Lamott: old reviews (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Gene Logsdon: At Nature's Pace: art/production (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Gene Logsdon: At Nature's Pace: author questionnaire (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Gene Logsdon: At Nature's Pace: contract (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Gene Logsdon: At Nature's Pace: copyediting (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Gene Logsdon: At Nature's Pace: editorial (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Gene Logsdon: At Nature's Pace: jacket copy (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Gene Logsdon: At Nature's Pace: presigning/ p & l (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Gene Logsdon: At Nature's Pace: subrights (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Gary Nabhan, Desert Follies and Borderline Fools: proposal (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Gary Nabhan, Desert of Spirits: proposal (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: art/production (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: author information (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: blurbs and reviews (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: contract (as Pilgrims) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: editorial (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: jacket copy (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: marketing/ publicity (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: permissions (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: proposal (as Pilgrims) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: presigning/ p & l (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Gary Nabhan, Songbirds, Truffles and Wolves: subrights (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Nabhan: old reviews (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Snyder: No Nature: art/production: cover (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Snyder: No Nature: art/production: layout (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Snyder: No Nature: art/production: text (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Snyder: No Nature: contract (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Snyder: No Nature: editorial: contents (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Snyder: No Nature: editorial: correspondence (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Snyder: No Nature: foreign rights (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Snyder: No Nature: gift lists (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Snyder: No Nature: index (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Snyder: No Nature: jacket copy (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Snyder: No Nature: marketing: background (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Snyder: No Nature: marketing: biographical information (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Snyder: No Nature: marketing: Nat'l Book Award (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Snyder: No Nature: marketing: reading schedules (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Snyder: No Nature: p & l (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Snyder: No Nature: permissions (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Snyder: No Nature: reviews (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Snyder: No Nature: paperback edition: editorial materials (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Snyder: No Nature: paperback ed.: promotional materials (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Snyder: old North Point reviews (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Pantheon West authors: computer sales (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Pantheon West authors: Aitken/Berry/Daniel/Davenport (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Pantheon West authors: Fisher/Lamott/Nabhan/Snyder (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Pantheon West authors: titles; general (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Pantheon West authors: interhouse correspondence (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Pantheon West authors: Pantheon overview and publicity (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Pantheon West authors: production schedules (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Pantheon West authors: West Coast office opening gala (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Series II: Pantheon Correspondence and Subject Files
  - A; general (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Academy of American Poets (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Kathy Acker (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Agents, Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Robert Aitken (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - ARG (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Arion Press (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Art of Action: sample (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Art of the Wild Conference: background (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Art of the Wild Conference: MS; A-G (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Art of the Wild Conference: MS; H-M (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Art of the Wild Conference: MS; P-Z (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Audio Press (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - B; general (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Bay Area Book Council and Festival (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Bay Area Book Reviewers' Awards, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Bericault (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Wendell Berry; contract negotiations (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Wendell Berry: correspondence (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Wendell Berry: essays and reprints (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Wendell Berry: gift/review lists (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Wendell Berry: honors (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Wendell Berry: photo project (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - E. Bishop Oral History Proposal (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Black Oak Books (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Black Sparrow Press (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Bill Bradley: Nat'l Press Club Speech, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Broken Moon Press (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - C; general (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Carroll Pub. Group (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hayden Carruth; "Suicide" reprint (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Julie Castiglia (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Chronicle Books (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - City Arts and Lectures (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Coffee House Press (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Cole /Lubenow: June Degman Proposal (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Evan Connell (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Joan Crane (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - D; general (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - John Daniel (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Guy Davenport (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Lane Dunlop (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - E; general (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Ecco Press (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - David Ehrenfeld (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Elliot Bay Books (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - F; general (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: Films (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: In Memoriam Articles (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - M.F.K. Fisher: proposals: books (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Ross Feld (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - G; general (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Robin Givens (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Tom Ginzberg (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Gnomon Press (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - H; general (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Hansel Hagel (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Shulamith Hareven (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Frederick Hill and Associates (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - I; general (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Island Institute (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - J; general (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Paul Jaffe; Dogen book (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Fenton Johnson (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Ron Johnson (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - K; general (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Michael Katz (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Kawabata: Asakusa book proposal (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Petra Kelly: reprint (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Stephen Kessler (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - David Kline (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Barbara Kouts (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - L; general (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Anne Lamott (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - James Lewis; draft: If the Body... (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - James Lewis: revision (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Lescher & Lescher (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Gordon Livingston (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Barry Lopez (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - M; general (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Marmur Associates (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Juliet Martin (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Carole Maso (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Sonny Mehta/ Jessica Green corresp. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - W.S. Merwin (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Joseph Mitchell (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - N; general (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Gary Nabhan (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Kafu Nagai (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - National Book Awards, 1992: program (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Nature Writing: misc. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - North Atlantic Books (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - North Point Press (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - O; general (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Orion Agency (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - P; general (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Camille Paglia (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Michael Palmer (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Parallax Press (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Andrew Porter (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Bill Porter on Sung Po-jen (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Al Poulin (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Q/R; general (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Clair Reiniger (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Lewis Richmond (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Carlos Rojas (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Muriel Rukeyser (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Peter Russell (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - S; general (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - James Salter (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Leslie Scalapino (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Schaffner Agency (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Shambhala Publications (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Jack Shoemaker (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Steve Shoemaker (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ed Snow on Rilke (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Gary Snyder: correspondence (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Gary Snyder: promotional (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Wallace Stegner: memorials and obituaries (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - T; general (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Moritz Thompson (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Fred Turner (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - U/V; general (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Erotic Stories; North Point Press project (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: new stories (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: editorial (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Claribel Alegria (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Helena Araujo (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Diamela Eltit (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Margo Glantz (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Antonieta Madrid (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Montserrat Ordonez (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Alicia Dujovne Ortiz (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Nelida Pinon (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Elena Poniatowska (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Cristina Peri Rossi (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Luisa Valenzuela: Ana Lydia Vega (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - W; general (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Burton Watson (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Anthony Weston (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Kathleen Wheater (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - White Pine Press (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - X/Y/Z; general (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Yolla Bolly Press (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Michael Zwerin (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Series III: Production and Promotion; Pantheon/ Interhouse (incl. Schocken)
  - production: Spring 1991 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - production: Fall 1991 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - production/sales: Fall 1992 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - sales conference: Fall 1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - tip sheets: Fall 1992 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - production: Winter 1992 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - publication schedules Winter 1992 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - sales: fact sheets, Winter 1992 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - production: Spring 1993 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - production Fall 1993 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - tip sheets Fall 1993 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - production Winter 1993 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - sales: Winter 1993 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - tip sheets: Winter 1993 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - tip sheets: Winter 1994 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - looseleaf notebook: "minutes" containing Pantheon/Schocken production information which duplicates much of series above in separate box (Box 15, Folder 15a)
- Series IV: Publishers (Incl. Pantheon non-list business)
  - Everyman (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Knopf (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pantheon: applicants (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Pantheon: Susan di Seca (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Pantheon: Alison Macondray (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Pantheon: misc. keepsakes and correspondences (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Pantheon: misc. publicity (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Pantheon: office business (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Pantheon: queries 1990-1 (includes items carried over from defunct North Point Press) (Box 16, Folder 9-12)
  - Pantheon: queries 1992 (Box 16, Folder 13-16)
  - Pantheon: queries 1993 (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
  - Pantheon: queries 1994 (Box 17, Folder 5-8)
  - Pantheon: Shoemaker lectures, appearances, etc. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Pantheon: Shoemaker and North Point Press (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Random House (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Schocken (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Series V: Personal Projects and Subject Files
  - Robert Aitken: Articles (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Robert Aitken and Brother David Dialogue: draft 1 (Box 18, Folder 2)